aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
I guess I woke you up.
깨워 버렸군
I will take your power.
그 힘을 넘겨받겠다
Strength to my Hands
힘을 나의 손에
Absorbent Alien Killad Seijin
Appears
흡수 우주인 키라드 성인 등장
The gorilla that disappeared yesterday in Sankai Zoo is still yet to be found.
어젯밤, 산카이 동물원에서 사라진 고릴라는 아직 발견되지 않았습니다
The police is considering the recent disappearance of animals that occurs in
최근 들어 발생한 동물의 잇다른 소실 사건
succession as a crime done by thieves who were looking for expensive animals and is
경찰에선 고가(高價)의 동물을 노린 절도단의 범행으로 보고
carrying out an investigation.
수사를 속행중입니다
What a dangerous world.
세상 참 무서워졌군
Yeah, we should arrive before we get atacked.
그럼, 습격당하기 전에 도착해야겠어
What's wrong? Are you hungry?
왜그래, 배라도 고프니?
-Yoshiko.
-Nemuta.
-요시코 씨.
-네무타 군.
A t- ti- tiger!
호, 호, 호랑이다!
Are you hurt?
다친 거니?
Calm down. I'm on your side.
안심해, 난 네 편이야
Good boy.
그래, 착하지
Alright, that'll do.
좋아, 다됐다
It'll be all right. You'll get better soon.
이제 괜찮아, 곧 좋아질 거야
It seems that I found a next prey.
다음 먹이를 발견했다
Who's there?
너는?
I was looking for you.
찾고 있었다
An alien from Sargasso?
사르갓소의 우주인?
Stop!
기다려!
That's a good action.
좋은 몸 동작이군
I won.
이겼다
You bastard!
이자식!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!!
Shadow Ryu!
섀도우 류!!
Oh, a transformation capability?
호오, 변신 능력인가?
Unforgivable!
용서 못한다!
You're pretty good. You're not running away next time!
제법 하는군, 다음엔 놓치지 않는다!
You won't run away!
놓치지 않는다!
What the-?!
아니!?
I'll take your power.
그 힘, 넘겨받겠다
No... way...
그, 그런!?
What an idiot. Well, it shouldn't matter anyway.
바보같은 녀석... 뭐, 상관없지
By this, I gained another strength.
이걸로 난 또 하나의 힘을 손에 넣었다
You bastard!
이자식!!
You still had powers for that?
호오, 아직 그런 힘이 남아 있었나?
N- no way! You injured me?!
마, 말도안돼!
내게 상처를!?
You punk!
이자식!!
What the-?!
아니!?
Stop. That's as far as you go.
잠깐, 거기까지다
Hey, Ryu! Are you on a secret date with an alien?
이봐, 류!
혼자서 우주인과 데이트냐?
You could have introduced him to us too!
우리들에게도 소개시켜 달라구
Everyone!
너희들...!
Are you okay, Ryu?
괜찮아, 류?
Interesting. What an interesting planet.
재미있어. 정말 재미있는 별이군
It's nice to know that there are so much strong guys like you.
이렇게나 강한 녀석들이 득실거리다니 말야
But I will become stronger.
하지만 난, 더욱 강해진다
S- stop!
기, 기다려!
I will finish this later on.
이 결판은 반드시 짓겠다
Stop!
기다려!!
Ryu!
류!
Are you alright?
괜찮아!?
Who the heck was that?
누구냐, 저녀석은?
Ryu!
류!
I will...
녀석은...
I will take care of that guy!
그녀석은 내가 해치운다!
I cannot forgive that guy, no matter what!
그녀석 만은 절대 용서할 수 없어!!
That alien from yesterday absorbed an animal?
동물을 흡수? 어제의 우주인이 말야?
Yeah. I saw it with my eyes.
그래, 이 눈으로 봤어
That was too much for yourself.
나 참, 무리나 하고 말야
Well, I hope you learned the preciousness of us, eh?
뭐, 이걸로 우리들의 소중함을 잘 알았겠지, 응?
Hmph, what a boring guy.
칫, 재미없는 녀석
So that would mean that the continuous disappearance of animals would be done by that guy.
그렇다면, 일련의 동물 실종사건도 녀석의 짓이겠군요
So it's an alien that becomes stronger by absorbing animals?
동물을 흡수해서 강해지는 우주인인가?
I will finish this later on.
이 결판은 반드시 짓겠다
It is an interesting one as a test subject, but an troublesome one as an enemy.
연구대상으로선 재미있을 것 같지만, 적으로선 성가신 녀석이군요
Ryu?
류?
I'm going to find him.
녀석을 찾으러 간다
What can you do with that body?
그 몸으로 뭘 할 수 있다는 거냐!?
A patient should act like a patient!
환자는 환자답게 있으라구!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Don't look me like that!
그런 눈으로 보지 말라구
It's not like I wanted to do this, but we can't leave you like that by yourself!
나도 이런 짓 하고 싶지 않지만 지금 널 혼자 내버려 둘 순 없잖아?
Hey, you should cool down and get your injury cured first.
그러니까, 조금은 머리를 식히고 천천히 상처를 치료하라구
Wait for a moment! I'll get you a lunch.
조금만 기다려, 지금 점심 사올테니까 말야
J- just a moment!
자, 잠깐 기다려!
Ryu, it's not like I wanted...
류... 나라고 해서 이런 짓을....
Hey, I guess you're good with fried noodles, right?
아, 넌 야키소바면 되겠지?
(역주 : 야키소바-국수를 야채·고기 등을 섞어 볶은 요리)
See ya!
그럼, 갔다올게
This is bad.
심각하군
All eliminated, even with tanks like these?
이정도의 전차가 달려들어도 전멸이란 말인가?
Yeah. Moreover, I heard that they had no time to request for SOS signal.
아아, 게다가 SOS를 보낼 틈도 없었다고...
Hey, you two, look at this!
저기 여러분, 이걸 보세요
It seems that it was ripped by sharp things like canine teeth and claws.
뭔가... 송곳니와 발톱 같은 것으로 심하게 찢은 것 같군
-Canine tooth?
-Could it be?
-송곳니?
-설마?!
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
I'm sorry, but did you see Ryu passing by?
미안해! 그쪽에 류가 가지 않았어!?
What? En, did you...
뭐야, 엔! 설마!?
So- sorry. He ran away!
미, 미안해. 도망쳤어
Ryu's taking danger!
위험하다구, 류 녀석!
En, listen carefully!
엔, 잘 들어!
That alien absorbs not only animals!
그 우주인이 흡수하는건 동물 뿐만이 아니야!
What?!
뭐야!?
It is a frightening alien that absorbs not only animals but also weapons!
녀석은 동물 뿐만 아니라 병기까지 자기 몸으로 흡수하는 무서운 우주인입니다!
I never thought you'd come first.
호오, 네놈 쪽에서 찾아올 줄이야
Doesn't matter. I will get rid of you this time.
상관없다 이번에야말로 네놈을 해치워주마
Because I cannot let anyone stronger than me.
나보다 강한 녀석을 내버려둘 수는 없으니까 말이다
Even if it's an inferior creature.
설사, 하등생물이라 할지라도 말이야
Pretty nice.
제법 하는군
There you are!
그곳이군!
Big Spiral Whirlwind Slash!
대회전 검풍참!!
-Commencing the attack to the target.
-Roger.
-지금부터 목표에게 공격을 개시한다
-라져
Alright, here it goes!
좋아, 간다!
The end.
여기까지다
You bastard!
이자식!
En!
엔!
Meddling with me again?
또 방해를 하는거냐!?
Right! Because he's my friend!
그래, 동료니까 말이다!
Friend?
흥, 동료라구?
What a bad joke.
웃기는군!
Face us! Your opponent are us!
잠깐 기다려! 너의 상대는 우리들이다!
-Stay put, En.
-Roger!
-물러나 있어라, 엔
-응!
Are you okay?
괜찮아?
I told you to stay off of this!
상관 말라고 했을텐데?
I told you that a patient should act like a patient.
환자는 환자답게 있으라고 했을텐데 말야
It's me who'll take that guy down!
녀석은... 내가 해치운다!
Stay off?
상관하지 말라고?
Be serious!
농담하지마!
We're thinking what you're thinking!
우리들의 마음은 너와 마찬가지일 거야!
What?!
뭐야?
We all share the will to stop bastards like that who messes up with the Earth!
저런 녀석에게 지구를 어지럽히고 싶지 않은 마음은 다들 같을 거라구!
En...
엔...
Fire Stratus!
파이어 스투라투스!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어!!
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!!
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터!!
Crystal Cutter!
크리스탈 커터!!
Do you really think you can defeat me?
진심으로 날 이길 거라고 생각하나?
Of course!
당연하지!
We did it!
해치웠다!
Now, you look! There's nobody stronger thna us!
자, 봐라! 우리들 이상으로 강한 녀석 따윈...
Oh, no!
앗, 큰일이다!
Thanks for the waiting!
기다리게 했구나!
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보!!
Friends are nothing more than a bunch of weaklings after all!
결국 동료 따윈 약해빠진 녀석들의 모임일 뿐이다!
There is only one strongest creature, and that is me!
최강의 생물은 단 하나! 바로 이몸이다!
Damn that guy!
제길, 저녀석!
Is it you again? How obstinate!
또 네놈이냐!? 성가신 녀석이군!
Shadow Jet!
섀도우 제트!!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우!!
No worth dealing with you!
별거 아니군!
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우!!
A... a little bit more...
조, 조금... 조금만 더...
Finally you're down.
이제서야 겨우 나자빠졌군
I do not know where did you obtain that power from...
어디에 그런 힘이 있는지는 모르겠지만...
but you'd better be happy to become a part of me!
내 일부가 되는걸 기뻐해라!
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우...!
Now!
지금이다!
Wh- what the?!
아, 아니!?
Wh- what's this?!
뭐, 뭐야!?
Wh- what happened?
어, 어째서 이런!?
That's enough!
거기까지다!
Shadow Claw!
섀도우 클로!!
What are you planning?!
어쩔 셈이냐!?
Dag Fire! This guy is full of oil inside!
다그 파이어! 지금 이녀석의 몸 안은 기름으로 가득 차 있어!
-Dag Shadow!
-Do it!
-다그 섀도우!
-부탁한다!
Alright.
알았어!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체(火炎合體)!!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!!
Unhand me! Let me go!
놔라! 놓으라구!!
Wh- why?! My power and firepower should be above them!
어, 어째서냐!? 힘도 화력도 내쪽이 위일 터다!
But why.....
그, 그런데 어째서...
Eat this! Fire Star Burn!
받아라! 파이어 스타 번!!
I- I lost? I hate this!
내, 내가 지다니!? 시, 싫어!!
I had my revenge.
원수는 갚았어
Thanks to all of them.
모두 저녀석들 덕분이야
What is he talking to himself?
뭘 혼자서 중얼대는거지, 저녀석?
I wonder he's all right. I hope him to stop making us worried...
괜찮을까? 이 이상 걱정시키지 말았으면 하는데...
Huh? Were you even worried?
에에? 걱정 같은걸 하고 계셨습니까?
Isn't that obvious?
당연하지!
H- hey! Don't push!
이, 이봐! 밀지 말라구
Where's Ryu?
류는?
Huh? Where did he go?
어레, 어디로 갔지?
-Hey, Ryu!
-Please come out, Ryu!
-어~이, 류!
-나와 주세요! 류 씨~
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
A foe, or an ally?
적인가, 아군인가
A swordsman that came from the other side of the space - Lian!
우주의 저편에서 온 우주 검사 라이안!
His mind is full of sadness and vengeance.
녀석의 마음은 슬픔과 복수로 가득 차 있어
You can't take down your arch enemy, Ark Seijin by yourself!
너의 숙적 아크 성인은 혼자서 쓰러뜨릴 수 있는 상대가 아니야!
Lian! Why aren't you fighting with us?!
라이안! 어째서 우리와 함께 싸우지 않는거야!?
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! 100,000 Light Years of Vengeance
다음회 용자지령 다그온
복수의 10만광년
Open your mind, Lian!
마음을 여는 거다, 라이안!!
100,000 Light Years of Vengeance
복수의 10만광년